では しばらくお待ちを
Wait here a moment.
本字幕由✿花語&花丸字幕組✿共同製作
ヤンクムジとの決戦まで 後一日
One day until the battle against Yan Kum-ji.
暗くて長い 夜の始まりだった
It was the beginning of a long, dark night.
It's pitch black.
真っ暗
どこかに運ばれている
Are we being taken somewhere?
大丈夫
It's okay.
商品の様子はどうだ
How are the goods?
They're doing fine.
問題ありません
先程 高く売れそうな商品が二人 手に入ったようです
We just acquired two that should fetch a high price.
一人は珍しい赤い髪の少女だとか
I'm told one has unusually red hair.
Oh?
赤い髪
Red hair...
O maiden!
otome yo
Flare up in the dawning sun!
akatsuki ni moeagare
I want to tear off the guise of the ignorant
muchi de kayowaku mamorareru dake no
Frail protected princess and live
hime nugisutete watashi wa ikitai
To conquer the color of the burning dawn
mukashi yori sukoshi dake suki ni nareta
That I've recently started enjoying
akatsuki no sora no iro nabikase
With strength and commanding presence
rinzen to tsuyoku
I strive to be someone I'm proud of
kedakaku sora wo miagete
And looking up idealistically to the sky
hokoreru jibun ni narou
To protect, to love, to stand my ground
mamori aishi tsuranuku
I won't allow myself to lose anything again
keshite ubawasenai
Like a noble flower
kedakai hana no you ni
With single-minded passion
hitamuki na jounetsu de
Even if faced with a cruel fate
zankoku na sadame sae
I will push through
kirihiraite miseru kara
Episode 21:         Spark
こんなことが ずっと昔から行われていたのね
This has been going on for a long time.
Get inside!
早く入れ
いってぇ
Ouch!
大丈夫
Are you okay?
捻挫してる
It's sprained.
落ちた時 足を痛めたんだ
You hurt your leg when you fell.
こんな時にこんな状態で計画通り動けるの
Will I be able to carry out our plan like this?
もし 失敗したら
If we fail...
ヤンクムジ
Yan Kum-ji!
成程 上物揃いだ
I see. You're all excellent.
阿波もまだまだ捨てたものではないな
Awa still has some value left in it.
クムジ様 どういうことですか
Lord Kum-ji, what is the meaning of this?
We came looking for work.
私達 仕事が頂けると聞いたここに
There is work.
仕事がある
Work so delightful that you
may not be able to handle it.
楽しい仕事がいやという程な
赤い髪か 確かに珍しい
Red hair? Unusual, indeed.
顔もなかなかの美形
Your face isn't bad, either.
売るのが少々惜しくなったわ
I almost regret having to sell you.
ヨナ
Yona!
With so many excellent goods,
これだけ上物が揃っていれば
一人くらい俺のものにしたところで そう損にもなるまい
keeping one for myself would be no great loss.
クムジ様
Lord Kum-ji!
そ そんな女より 私の方がきっとご満足いただけますわ
I-I'm sure I can satisfy you better than she can.
おぉっと 何を言ってるのかな 俺
Ugh! What am I saying?
Oh?
そんな女ほっといて どうか私をお側に
Forget about her. Choose me instead.
No, no. Who do you think you are?
いやいや 誰だお前 男だってばれたら 即殺されるって
Once he finds out you're a man, he'll kill you.
でも 約束したから
But I promised I'd protect Yona.
ヨナを守るって
お前もなかなかの上玉だ
You're quite beautiful, as well.
But...
Don't interrupt me while I'm having fun!
俺が楽しんでる時に 口を挟むんじゃない
クムジ様 商品に傷が
Lord Kum-ji, you'll damage the merchandise.
口を挟むなと言ったはずだ
What did I say about interrupting me?
いいぞ いいぞ
Good, good.
女は従順で黙って震えているのが一番だ
Nothing pleases me more than obedient women who tremble in silence.
この赤毛の女のようにな
Just like this redhead.
What?
なんだ
威圧感
Did she intimidate me?
こんな小娘に
This little girl?
いや 待ってよ
No, wait.
娘 お前は阿波の人間か
Girl, are you from Awa?
はい
Yes.
その昔 俺は一度だけ緋龍城にてお前と同じ赤い髪を見たことがある
Long ago, I once saw red hair
like yours at Hiryuu Castle.
一瞬だけ
For just a moment, in the distance,
I saw her hair reflecting the sun.
遠くから日の光に反射するその髪の女の名は
ヨナ姫
The girl was Princess Yona.
年の頃なら お前と同じくらいだ
She was around your age.
まさかお前 ヨナ姫か
Are you Princess Yona?
He noticed!
気づかれた
私は阿波の貧しい商人の娘
I'm the daughter of a poor Awa merchant.
ここで新しい仕事を頂けると聞いて参りました
I came because I heard you were offering work.
赤い髪のお姫様は存じ上げませんが
I don't know your red-headed princess,
クムジ様のお仕事で
but if being her would please you,
そのお姫様となった方がよろしければ
ヨナ姫と名乗らせていただきます
I will call myself "Princess Yona."
戯れが過ぎたか
I let myself go too far.
ヨナ姫がお前の様に
Unlike you, Princess Yona
would be too self-respecting
仕事欲しさから 床に頭を擦り付け
to rub her face on the ground and grovel before me for work, filthy wench!
俺のような者に抗弁を垂れる 自尊心なき者ではないわ
そうだ 何をバカなことを
That's right. How could I be so stupid?
第一 あの姫は 従者に連れ去られ 殺されたと聞く
I heard the princess was carried off
by attendants and killed.
イル王の庇護の元 飴のように甘やかに育てられた姫が
A daughter brought up under King Il's
protective pampering...
野生の獣のような目をするはずがない
wouldn't have the eyes of a wild beast.
ユン しっかり
Yun!
Hang in there!
もう か弱い美少女を蹴るなんて最低
Who kicks a cute, delicate little girl? What a jerk.
ユン
Yun...
Yona, your foot is turning blue.
ヨナこそ 足 青くなってるよ 痛いでしょう
It must hurt.
全然
I'm fine. I'd forgotten about the pain.
痛みなんて忘れてたわ
面白くなってきたじゃない
Things are starting to get interesting.
俺は痛みは忘れないよ
I'm not about to forget my pain.
百倍にして返ってしてやるからね
I'll pay him back a hundred times over.
What Lord Kum-ji said...
さっきのクムジ様のお話
Does he plan to sell us?
売るって 私達を
出して ここから出して
Let us out! Let us out of here!
ね 誰か
Someone...
Someone help! Somebody, please!
誰か助けて 誰か
There's no point.
無駄よ
私は二週間前からここに入れられてるの
I've been in here for two weeks.
泣いたって叫んだって 誰にも届かないわ
You can cry or scream,
but no one will hear you.
クムジ様にとって私等なんか
金儲けの道具でしかないの
Lord Kum-ji only sees us
as a source of money.
この町はずっとそいう所だったでしょう
This city has always been that way.
変えたいと思ったことはない
Have you ever wanted to change that?
なにを
Change what?
この町を...
This place.
この町からヤンクムジを退けて
Have you ever thought about
fighting Yan Kum-ji...
皆が自由に暮らせるように戦おうと思った事はない
and running him out of town
so you can all live here freely?
なに
What?
あんた本当にこの町の人間
Are you really from this town?
そんなこと言うのは
The only people who talk like that are outsiders and the strong.
外の人間と強い人間 後はよっぽとのバカよ
And idiots too.
特別強くもないけれど
I'm not particularly strong,
この町を変えようよ命懸けで戦ってる人達を私は知ってる
but I know people who are risking their lives to change this town.
そんなバカを支えようとする
もっと頼れない女の子もいるけどね
And there's an even more powerless girl who's trying to support those idiots.
それ 誰のこと ユン
Who are you talking about, Yun?
なにを言ってるの
What are you talking about?
誰か助けに来てくれるっての
Is someone coming to rescue us?
そんなバカいないわよ
No one's that stupid.
それは分からない
I don't know about that.
でも 貴方達の言うバカが手を差し伸べたら
But if one of those idiots of yours
reaches out to save you,
信じて その手を握り返して
you should trust them and take their hand.
生きたいと思うのなら どうか
If you want to live, please...
死に物狂いで 生き抜いて
do everything you can to survive.
確かに私はなんの力もありません
I know that I have no strength to offer.
歯痒い程に 決して強くもありません
It irritates me how weak I am.
でも どうか守らせて
But let me protect them!
この国の姫として ただ一人の人間として 戦わせてください
As this kingdom's princess, and as any other human being, please let me fight.
Hak...
ハク
少しは休みなよ
Get some rest. You've been standing like that since yesterday.
昨日からずっと同じ姿で
This is how I sleep.
俺はこうやって寝る趣味だ
それにそのセリフは 白蛇に言ってやれ
Besides, you should tell that
to the White Snake.
兄ちゃん また夢見てんぞ
Damn you, Kum-ji!
Hey, you're dreaming again.
オノレ クムジ
許さんな
You'll pay for this!
なんだあれは
What's he doing?
Every time he nods off, he jumps up to pick a fight with the air.
時折うとうとしては飛び起きて空中に喧嘩を売ってるからな
Good grief.
綺麗な顔が台無しだね キジャ君は
Ki-ja's ruining his good looks.
緑龍 目の下 黒い
Green Dragon, you have dark rings under your eyes.
Don't sneak up on me like that, Sin-ha.
背後で呟かないでくれるかな シンア君
緑龍も 寝てない
You haven't slept either.
僕が まさか
Who, me? Don't be absurd.
僕はよく食べ よく眠ったし
I ate well and slept well.
夕べは女の子とも遊んで もう余裕余裕
I even had some fun with the ladies last night.
I'm the very image of composure.
Huh?
顔を見せろ
Let me see your face!
何するんだい ちょっと
What are you doing?
目を見せるのだ
Show me your eyes!
キジャ君 君の手 刺さる 刺さるから
Ki-ja, you're stabbing me with your hand!
こっち向け
Look this way!
I've been defiled,
汚された
but that hurt so good.
でもちょっと いた気持ちよかった
Dark Circles
Keep your clothes on.
脱ぐな
You have dark rings under your eyes!
あったぞ 目の下にクマ
だから 昨日の夜は女の子と...
I told you. I had fun with the ladies last-
緑龍 昨日はずっと見張り台にいた
Green Dragon, you were in
the crow's nest all last night.
よく見てるね
You've been watching me pretty closely.
Come on, now. Do you love me that much?
やだな 僕って愛されてる
そなたもあの方が心配で 堪らないのだな
You're worried about her too, aren't you?
だからなに
So what if I am?
そりゃ僕はヨナちゃんが心配だよ
Of course I'm worried about Yona.
当然だろ ヨナちゃんは女の子だから
Who wouldn't be? She's a girl, after all.
なんでもよい
Whatever your reason,
as long as we feel the same way,
そなたが私と同じ気持ちならば
それだけで 背中を預けて戦えるのだから
I can trust you to watch my back in a fight.
勝手にしな
Do as you please.
でも あの子は心配しなくていいの
But shouldn't you be worried about him?
ほら よくしゃべる可愛い子
You know, the cute, talkative one.
Yun, right?
ユン君だっけ
あの子も力なさそうだし 危ないと思うけど
He seems pretty weak too.
He could be in danger.
あいつは大丈夫だ
He'll be fine.
うむ ユンは年若いのに敏く 努力家だ
That's right. For his age, Yun is very clever and hard-working.
私は時折 あの者に尊敬すら覚えるぞ
Sometimes, I'm even in awe of him.
シンア
Sin-ha.
港の船 動き出した
The ships in the harbor are moving.
お前達 そろそろだよ
It's time, boys.
今宵 我らが狙うとびっきりのお宝は
Tonight, our eyes are set on
the greatest treasure of all:
阿波の町の領主 ヤンクムジの首一つ
the head of Yan Kum-ji, Lord of Awa!
Yeah!
アオ
Ao.
おい 何を騒いで...
Hey! What's all the-
Huh?
おい 今騒いでた奴は
Hey, who was making all that racket?
Damned girl.
小娘
どうやって縄を解いた
How did you undo the ropes?
大人しく
Stay-
セーノ
Down!
し 死んだ
I-Is he dead?
いや
No. The anesthetic I rubbed on the needle just knocked him out.
最初に打った麻酔針が効いて 気絶しただけ
これで半日は起きない
He'll sleep for half a day.
あんた達 本当に逃げ出すつもり
Are you really trying to escape?
あんた 震えているの
Are you shaking?
足も 怪我してるじゃない
Your leg is injured, as well.
そんなんでよくあんな事できるわね
I'm impressed you pulled
that off in your condition.
Don't do this. We don't want to get involved.
止してよ 私達を巻き込まないで
私 貴方達を助けに来たの
I came to rescue you.
助ける
Rescue us?
この船の場所を仲間に教えるのが
Our job is to signal the ship's position to our allies.
私達の仕事
けど どうやって教えるの
But how?
船は港を出たし ここは海の上なのに
The ships have left the harbor. We're in the middle of the sea.
甲板に上がって花火を上げる
I'm going up on deck and launching a signal.
Huh?
It's a small firework,
but I'm sure our allies will notice.
小さい花火だけど 仲間がきっと見つけてくれる
仲間も海の上にいるの
They're out at sea too.
待ってて 必ず助けるから
Wait here. I promise we'll rescue you.
行こう
Let's go.
Okay.
変えたいと思ったことはない
Have you ever wanted to change that?
この町を
This place.
待って
Wait!
外は役人がうようよ居る
It's swarming with officials out there.
私も手伝うわ
I'll help.
Huh?
私の父さん船大工なの
My father builds ships.
船の作りには詳しいから 近道は案内できる
I know a lot about how boats are constructed. I can show you a shortcut.
ありがとう
Thank you!
But why?
でも どうして
さっき私達に言ったでしょう
You said so yourself.
助けが来たら信じてその手を握り返せって
When help arrives, we should
have faith and take their hand.
この町を変えたい
We too want to change...
私達も
this town.
私の名前はユリ
My name is Yuri.
私はヨ...えっと リナ
My name is Yo-
Uh, Rina.
おれあぁ...私はユン
I'm, uh...
I'm Yun. Try not to slow us down.
足を引っ張らないでよね
あんた生意気ね
You're sassy, aren't you?
It's started.
始まった
Yes.
クムジはどやつだ
Where is Kum-ji?
I'll kill him!
私が討取ってくれる
Don't pass out from all the excitement, White Snake.
燥ぎ過ぎて貧血起こすなよ 白蛇
I'm not a white snake!
白蛇ではない
シンア 姫さんは
Sin-ha, where's the princess?
まだ 見当たらない
I don't see her yet.
手加減しろよ 後で婆さんが怒る
Don't kill them. You'll be in trouble
with the old lady later.
婆さんなんて言ったら 船長に殺されるよ ハク
The captain would kill you
if she heard you call her that, Hak.
しかし 数多いな
There sure are a lot of them, though.
Kum-ji seems to have hired
a bunch of mercenaries.
クムジが傭兵を山ほど雇ったみたいだね
姫さん ユン とっとと出てこい
Princess, Yun, get out here already!
Damn it. There's no end to them.
クソ なんて数だ
クムジは今夜こそ 俺らを潰す腹なんだろうよ
Kum-ji means to destroy us tonight.
Jae-ha?
ジェハ
You're already tired? But you're so young.
若いのに もうばてたの
I'm just getting started!
これからは見せ場だったんだよ
一晩中飛び回って 仲間助っ人する気かなぁ
Is he going to jump around all night,
helping people out?
Not even Jae-ha can keep that up.
いくらジェハでも体が持たないんじゃ
でも ジェハだから
But that's Jae-ha for you.
愈々海賊共と決戦か
Finally, it's time for our showdown with the pirates.
We hired all those mercenaries.
あれだけの傭兵がいるんだ
They won't reach this ship.
この船までは来ねぇんさ
楽な戦いだ
It'll be an easy battle.
女だ 女が脱走した
A woman! A woman escaped!
待って
Stop!
バカ目 行き止まりだ
Fool. That's a dead end.
Give yourself up!
観念しろ
ちょっとの間 眠ってておじさん
Time for you to take a nap, mister.
しまった
Crap!
動くな
Don't move!
Yuri!
ユリ
私達は大事な商品でしょう
Aren't we your precious goods?
If you hurt someone by swinging that around, Lord Kum-ji will-
そんなもの振り回して傷付けたらクムジ様が...
You're defective products that tried to escape!
お前等は脱走した不良品だ
阿波の人間が二度と逆らえないように見せしめに殺す
I'll make an example of you so the Awa citizens will never rebel again.
やめて ユリは関係ない
Stop! Yuri has nothing to do with this!
どうする
What should I do?
花火は俺が持っている
I have the firework.
急いで甲板に出て海賊に知らせて
I could rush onto the deck and signal the pirates.
No, that would endanger Yona and Yuri.
ダメだ それじゃヨナとユリが危ない
俺も甲板で捕まったら
If I got caught on deck...
This is terrible.
最悪だ
こんなところで花火も上げられず
We're stuck here, unable to launch the signal.
どうする どうする
What should I do? What should I do?
どうする
What should I do?
昔の俺だったら 自分の命を最優先に考えた
The old me would have prioritized my own life.
自分が逃げ切る一番効率のいい方法を考えた
I would have thought of the most
effective way for me to escape.
でも 今は...
But now...
イクス 俺 バカになったのかも
I think I might have become an idiot, Ik-su.
ヨナの勇気を無駄になんてさせない
Yona's courage...
I won't let her courage go to waste.
Huh?
I threatened them into helping me.
この二人は俺に落とされて協力しただけだよ
本当に無関係だから 許してやって
They have nothing to do with this, so let them go.
A man?
男
I'm actually a pirate.
俺は実は海賊でこの船に密偵として入り込んでたんだよね
I stowed away on this ship as a spy.
A pirate?
海賊だと
Damn you!
この野郎
Don't think we'll show any mercy, pirate!
海賊なら尚更容赦しねぇ
ふざけやって
How dare you mock us?
I'll beat you to death!
殴り殺してやる
やめて
Stop!
ちょっと待った 話があるんだよ
Wait. I have something to tell you.
I've rigged the deck with explosives.
俺さ この船の甲板に爆薬仕掛けたんだよね
Rigged the deck with explosives?
甲板に爆薬だと
止めないと もうすぐ爆発するよ
If I don't stop them, they'll explode soon.
嘘をつけ 甲板にそんなものなかった
Liar! There wasn't anything like that on deck.
そりゃそうだろ 場所は俺しか知らねぇもん
Of course not. Only I know where they are.
黙って殺されるものか
I'm not going down without a fight.
とにかく甲板に出れば
シンアに見つけてもらえば なんとかなる
If I can get on deck and Sin-ha sees us,
we can still pull this off.
What should we do?
どうする
クソ
Damn it!
お前はその女達を下に連れ戻せ
You take the women back down.
俺はこいつを甲板に連れていく
I'll take this guy to the deck.
And?
Explosives or not, I'll cut off his head before returning him to the pirates.
爆薬があってもなくても
こいつの首を刎ねて海賊共に返してやるのさ
来い
Come!
Yun!
ユン
Hey, behave yourself!
大人しくしろ
Come on, get moving!
ほら 早く行け
どこへ行く お前は下...
Where are you going?
I'm taking you down to-
こ 此奴...
Y-You little...
What?
Wait!
待って
どこだ どこに仕掛けた
Where? Where are they?
There's nothing here!
どこにもねぇじゃねか
だから こっちじゃなくてもっと先だよ
They aren't over here.
They're farther down, near the bow.
チクショウ ここからじゃ死角で見えない
Damn it. We're in a blind spot.
もっと空が開けたところじゃなきゃ
I need to get somewhere more open.
やっぱり嘘か
I knew you were lying.
首を落として仲間のところに返してやるよ 海賊
I'll cut off your head and send you back to your buddies, pirate.
ヨナ
Yona?
ユンから離れなさい
Get away from Yun.
近づいたものは 打つ
I'll shoot anyone who approaches him.
なんだ さっきの小娘か
Oh, it's the girl from before.
そんなヘロヘロ矢で 何をするって
How are you going to shoot anyone with-
Yona!
ヨナ
Light the gunpowder quickly with that flame!
俺の爆薬を早くあの火に
ユン 火薬は
Yun, do you have the gunpowder?
帯の中に仕込んでる
It's inside my sash.
Get her!
捕まえろ
上がれ
Launch!
よかった
It launched!
Crying tears for the days that won't return
modoranai hibi ni namida koboshite
You look up to the sky, and it's burning bright red
miageta sora ga akaku akaku moeru
Now that you know your own strength and weakness
jibun no tsuyosa yowasa kizuketa no nara ima
You should have no fear and go where your heart takes you
kimi yo osoreruna kokoro omomuku mama
Cleaving through the wind, your path is lit
kaze wo kirisusumu sono tabiji wo
By the dawn
akatsuki ga terasu
(Gather, fierce arm)
(tsudoe takeki kaina)
(All-seeing eyes)
(senri no hitomi)
Feet that dash through the sky
sora wo kakeyuku ashi
(Shield of eternity)
(kuon no tate)
Fulfill the ancient vows
inishie no chikai ima hatashite
O night, break into dawn
yoru yo akete yuke
Next Time
父上 少しは私 強くなれましたか
Father, have I become stronger?
次回 暁のヨナ 第二十二話
Next time, Akatsuki no Yona, episode 22:
Episode 22:         The Night History Is Made
歴史は夜つくられる
The Night History Is Made.